U.S. Economic Stabilization Program Records 5464
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Economic Stabilization Program Records
1971-1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Economic Stabilization Program
5464
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of correspondence, agendas, policy papers, weekly reports, minutes, Pay board proceedings, and activity reports for the Economic Stabilization Program.
5623358
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 14, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
United States. Office of Economic Stabilization.
5623358
- Code of Federal Regulations, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Amendments to federal regulations concerning the pay board (June & July 1972)
- Correspondence - (News releases, telegrams, letters, newspaper clippings), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Dec. 1971 - Aug. 1972.
- Agendas and Policy Papers - Agendas, policy papers on agendas. (Jan. 1972 - Aug. 1972) Also tentative agendas. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Weekly Status Reports (Box 1, Folder 4)
  includes minutes, summary of case inventories, regulations, compliance matters, interpretations, press releases, and IRS or COLC weekly report.
- Minutes, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  draft minutes of board meetings and index to minutes (June - Aug. 1972)
- Payboard Proceedings, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  includes summaries of activities, minutes, cases and Appeals Panel Summaries, List of cases, Congressional Activities, Press Releases, News coverage highlights, speaker's list, and regulations (May - July 1972).
- Activities Reports, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Minutes of Pay Board cases and Appeals panel (March - April 1972)
- Cases Potentially Challengeable by Pay Board, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Jan. 1972-Aug. 1972
- Summaries of Cases, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  including State of Ohio Civil Service Employees Feb. 24, 1972; East and Gulf Coast Longshore (both summary and application to Pay Board). May 2, 1972; New York Firefighters, June 27, 1972; Aerospace Cases, Nov.-Dec. 1971
- Miscellaneous Papers (Box 2, Folder 6)
  includes booklets received; "Portrait of the Pay Board", "Meany on Controls," Economics of Wage and Price Controls by J.E. Pohlman; and "Pay Board Specialists' Manual."